<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://rchurch4.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://rchurch4.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-02T15:30:33-08:00</updated><id>https://rchurch4.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Rob Churchill</title><subtitle>Rob Churchill has a Ph.D. in Computer Science from Georgetown University.  His dissertation topic was Modernizing Topic Models Accounting for Noise, Time, and Domain Knowledge.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Industry</title><link href="https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/09/experience.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Industry" /><published>2022-08-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-08-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/09/experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/09/experience.html">&lt;p&gt;During and after the completion of my Ph.D., I have held a number of positions outside of the realm of research.  I am currently the Head of Data Science at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.5out.io/&quot;&gt;5-Out&lt;/a&gt;, a predictive analytics startup focused on providing restaurants with accurate and insightful forecasts for things like revenue, staffing requirements, inventory management, and food prep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to that, I was a data science and machine learning consultant at 5-Out (January 2022-July 2022).
In 2020 and early 2021, I was a consultant to a group of investors, conducting due diligence on a prospective investment in a cryptocurrency startup and a sports gambling startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between 2015 and 2021, I was a software engineering and data science consultant for Churchill Engineers in New Jersey, where I performed various services to improve the productivity of the accounting department and project managers.  I reverse-engineered obfuscated database schemas and wrote a number of SQL reports to streamline the workflow of accountants.  I also designed and built a web application using the python Django web framework that enables project managers to easily and efficiently track the progress of employees in the field.  The application, called Inspector DataBase &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.churchillidb.com&quot;&gt;(IDB)&lt;/a&gt;, allows managers to quickly visualize employees whose jobs are almost over, who are due for raises, who need to renew certifications, and a plethora of other information.  It saves them hours of work every time a new job proposal is written, and helps employees get matched to projects so that as few people are idle as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summer 2016, I worked as a software engineering intern at a startup called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spotfund.com/&quot;&gt;Spotfund&lt;/a&gt;.  At Spotfund, I designed and implemented a recommendation system for categorizing charities based on their official descriptions, names, and related charities.  I also designed and implented an analytics and accounting reconciliation platform.  Outside of the data science realm, I implemented backend features for the Spotfund platform using the Django web framework, and customized a URL shortener to incorporate deeplinks in order to track marketing efforts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">During and after the completion of my Ph.D., I have held a number of positions outside of the realm of research. I am currently the Head of Data Science at 5-Out, a predictive analytics startup focused on providing restaurants with accurate and insightful forecasts for things like revenue, staffing requirements, inventory management, and food prep.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://rchurch4.github.io/assets/images/ski4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://rchurch4.github.io/assets/images/ski4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Publications</title><link href="https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/08/publications.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Publications" /><published>2022-08-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-08-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/08/publications</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/08/publications.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a list of all of my publications so far (last updated August 9, 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rob Churchill and Lisa Singh. Using topic-noise models to generate domain-specific topics across data sources. In Knowledge and Information Systems (KAIS), 2023. &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/kais2023_arxiv.pdf&quot;&gt;(pdf)&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rob Churchill and Lisa Singh. Temporal Topic-Noise Models for Social Media Data Sets. In Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (PAKDD), 2022. &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/dynamic_topic_noise_models.pdf&quot;&gt;(pdf)&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rob Churchill, Lisa Singh, Rebecca Ryan, and Pamela Davis-Kean. A Guided Topic Model for Social Media Data. In The Web Conference (WWW), 2022. &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/guided_topic_model.pdf&quot;&gt;(pdf)&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;(Doctoral Thesis) Rob Churchill. Modernizing Topic Models: Accounting for Noise, Time, and Domain Knowledge. Diss. Georgetown University, 2021. &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/modernizing_topic_models.pdf&quot;&gt;(pdf)&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jaren Haber, Lisa Singh, Ceren Budak, Josh Pasek, Meena Balan, Ryan Callahan, Rob Churchill, Brandon Herren, Kornraphop Kawintiranon. Research Note: Lies and presidential debates: How political misinformation spread across media streams during the 2020 election. Harvard Kennedy School Misinformation Review, 2021. &lt;a href=&quot;https://misinforeview.hks.harvard.edu/article/research-note-lies-and-presidential-debates-how-political-misinformation-spread-across-media-streams-during-the-2020-election/&quot;&gt;(html)&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rob Churchill and Lisa Singh. Topic-Noise Models: Modeling Topic and Noise Distributions in Social Media Post Collections. In International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), 2021. &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/topic_noise_models.pdf&quot;&gt;(pdf)&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rob Churchill and Lisa Singh. The evolution of topic modeling. In ACM Computing Surveys (CSUR), 2021. &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/evolution_of_topic_modeling.pdf&quot;&gt;(pdf)&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rob Churchill and Lisa Singh. textPrep: A text preprocessing toolkit for topic modeling on social media data. In The DATA Conference, 2021. &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/textprep.pdf&quot;&gt;(pdf)&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rob Churchill and Lisa Singh. Percolation-based topic modeling for tweets. In KDD Workshop on Issues of Sentiment Discovery and Opinion Mining (WISDOM), 2020. &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/percolation_based_topic_modeling.pdf&quot;&gt;(pdf)&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rob Churchill, Lisa Singh, and Josh Pasek. The impact of pre-processing classes on meaningful topics from online text data. In MIDAS Symposium, 2018. 
    &lt;li&gt;Rob Churchill, Lisa Singh, and Christo Kirov. A temporal topic model for noisy mediums. In Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (PAKDD), 2018. &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/temporal_topic_model_for_noisy_mediums.pdf&quot;&gt;(pdf)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a list of all of my publications so far (last updated August 9, 2021):</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://rchurch4.github.io/assets/images/badlands.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://rchurch4.github.io/assets/images/badlands.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Research</title><link href="https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/08/research.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Research" /><published>2022-08-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-08-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/08/research</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/08/research.html">&lt;p&gt;As a Ph.D. student at Georgetown University, I was advised by Lisa Singh, and was part of the Georgetown DataLab and the Massive Data Institute.  My research area revolved around adapting topic models to social media data, and culminated in my doctoral thesis, &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/modernizing_topic_models.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modernizing Topic Models: Accounting for Noise, Time, and Domain Knowledge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  My research was focused on improving the interpretability of topics by humans, as well as the overall performance of topic models on short documents such as social media posts and survey data.  In the course of our research, I got to interact with a lot of very cool data sets in close to real time, including data sets pertaining to the 2016 and 2020 presidential elections, the Covid-19 pandemic, and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main contribution of my thesis was the invention of &lt;em&gt;topic-noise models&lt;/em&gt;, which combine a topic-word distribution with a global noise distribution to effectively filter noise from topics generated on social media data.  We have since adapted topic-noise models to incorporate a temporal aspect (&lt;em&gt;Dynamic Topic-Noise Models&lt;/em&gt;), and to incorporate the domain knowledge of the user (&lt;em&gt;Guided Topic-Noise Models&lt;/em&gt;).  The relevant papers can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/08/08/publications.html&quot;&gt;Publications page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way to creating topic-noise models, we created a framework for preprocessing text data for topic modeling &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GU-DataLab/topic-modeling-textPrep&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;TextPrep&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;, and a few other topic models which were based on a graph structure instead of a probability distribution, like the Dirichlet for LDA and our topic-noise models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We put together all of our topic models (as well as our own implementations of a couple very popular topic models) in a python package called GDTM (Georgetown Datalab Topic Models), which can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GU-DataLab/gdtm&quot;&gt;on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also published a survey of topic models called The Evolution of Topic Modeling, which carefully traces the origins of different facets of modern topic models to give a better understanding of how we came to be where we are today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current main research interests include topic modeling and time series analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As a Ph.D. student at Georgetown University, I was advised by Lisa Singh, and was part of the Georgetown DataLab and the Massive Data Institute. My research area revolved around adapting topic models to social media data, and culminated in my doctoral thesis, Modernizing Topic Models: Accounting for Noise, Time, and Domain Knowledge. My research was focused on improving the interpretability of topics by humans, as well as the overall performance of topic models on short documents such as social media posts and survey data. In the course of our research, I got to interact with a lot of very cool data sets in close to real time, including data sets pertaining to the 2016 and 2020 presidential elections, the Covid-19 pandemic, and others.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://rchurch4.github.io/assets/images/beach.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://rchurch4.github.io/assets/images/beach.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">About</title><link href="https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/06/about.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="About" /><published>2022-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/06/about</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/06/about.html">&lt;p&gt;I graduated with a Ph.D. in Computer Science from Georgetown University in May 2022, after defending my dissertation in December 2021.  Prior to that, I completed my Master’s degree in Computer Science at Georgetown in 2017, and my Bachelor’s degree at Boston University in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my Master’s and Ph.D. I was advised by Lisa Singh and worked in her research group, the Georgetown DataLab, and in conjunction with the Massive Data Institute (MDI) at the McCourt School of Public Policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m not working, you can find me surfing, skiing, kitesurfing or playing ice hockey.  I was a captain of the Georgetown Club Ice Hockey team as a grad student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the pictures on this website were taken of or by me while traveling.  I have been all over, but there’s still much more to explore!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/lisa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rob and Lisa&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I graduated with a Ph.D. in Computer Science from Georgetown University in May 2022, after defending my dissertation in December 2021. Prior to that, I completed my Master’s degree in Computer Science at Georgetown in 2017, and my Bachelor’s degree at Boston University in 2015.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://rchurch4.github.io/assets/images/surf5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://rchurch4.github.io/assets/images/surf5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Teaching</title><link href="https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/06/teaching.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Teaching" /><published>2022-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/06/teaching</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://rchurch4.github.io/2022/08/06/teaching.html">&lt;p&gt;Throughout my time as a graduate student, I was a teaching assistant many times.  Between 2016 and 2021, I was a TA for Data Science (Fall 2016, Fall 2019, Fall 2021), and Databases (Spring 2016, Spring 2018).
I also helped teach at &lt;a href=&quot;https://guwecode.georgetown.domains/&quot;&gt;Georgetown University Women Coders&lt;/a&gt; events from 2016 to 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love teaching and am looking forward to getting back to teaching at some point in my career!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Throughout my time as a graduate student, I was a teaching assistant many times. Between 2016 and 2021, I was a TA for Data Science (Fall 2016, Fall 2019, Fall 2021), and Databases (Spring 2016, Spring 2018). I also helped teach at Georgetown University Women Coders events from 2016 to 2021.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://rchurch4.github.io/assets/images/ski2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://rchurch4.github.io/assets/images/ski2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>